Hannah Carnes

Full stack web developer with a passion for collaborative problem solving. After working with developers in a previous role, I discovered web development as an opportunity for me to leverage my creativity and analytical skill set. I have experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Angular, and React, as well as project management and technical writing.

Technical Skills

TypeScript, React, Angular, RxJS, AWS, Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Git, Excel

Technical Projects

Greenthumb, 🕞 , 🛅 .

- o An app that allows users to search for community gardens in NYC, locate the garden on a map, and add plants.
 - Built custom user interface using ES6 JavaScript, React and Redux
 - Created Rails API to handle the data persistence; used async actions to send data to and from a server
 - Designed custom front-end using Material components

Socratic, 🕞 , 🛅 .

- A collaborative question and answer app for employees at small organizations
 - Designed the database schema and configured ActiveRecord associations
 - Used Devise and Omniauth for user authentication through Google
 - Designed custom front-end using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery

Bidify, 🕞 , 🛅 .

- An auction app that allows users to place items for bid and to bid on posted items
 - Used MVC design pattern to create a Sinatra CRUD app
 - Implemented user authentication and custom validations for user input using ActiveRecord
 - Designed the database schema and configured ActiveRecord associations

Artsy Scraper, 🕞 , 🛅 .

- o A virtual art gallery in your command line that lists artwork genes and prints art based on the user's selection
 - Used OO design patterns and scraped data using Selenium Webdriver

Employment History

9/2016 - 10/2017 Grant Administrator, Children's Advocacy Centers of Texas, Austin, TX.

- o Met annual goal of processing \$11 million in grant reimbursement requests across 70 local centers
- o Consulted with clients at local centers to meet business goals
- o Created macros in Excel VBA to automate tasks to increase efficiency in grants management process

2/2016 - 10/2017 **Grants Manager**, Explore Austin, Austin, TX.

- Developed and managed prospect research agenda for \$500,000 grant portfolio
- Wrote 3-5 proposals weekly to meet funding goals; secured \$50,000 in first-time donor funding

8/2014 - 2/2016 Grants Coordinator, Boys and Girls Clubs of Metro Atlanta, Atlanta, GA.

- o Procured and managed federal grant across 22 sites for Child and Adult Care Food Program, resulting in \$100,000 of new funding for meals at local centers
- · Led trainings for site staff to ensure grant compliance, resulting in successful external grant audits

Education

Flatiron School, Web Development Bootcamp, 2018, New York, NY

Master of Public Policy, 2014, Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Art Studies, 2009, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX